merrickbank.com 2010-06-21

# Merrick Bank Privacy Pledge to Our Customers

##  Protecting Your Privacy

Our Privacy Pledge is provided to help you understand how we protect your financial privacy. It provides you with an opportunity to make informed choices about the management of personal information about you. At Merrick Bank, we maintain high standards to safeguard Personal Information. We will remain vigilant in protecting that information and in using it in a fair and lawful manner. 

This Pledge explains our privacy commitment. It is not intended to be a contract. It identifies the Personal Information that we collect and hold, and describes how we use, share and secure it. It also tells you how to contact us if you have any questions regarding this Pledge or our privacy practices. 

To whom and what does this Pledge apply?

This Pledge covers the Personal Information of current and former individual Merrick Bank customers.

Our Pledge applies to all personally identifiable financial information about you that is obtained by Merrick Bank in connection with providing a consumer financial product or service for personal, family or household purposes. 

What Personal Information do we collect and how do we collect it? 

Based on our relationship with you, we collect Personal Information from and about you that is adequate, relevant and appropriate under the circumstances. For example, we may collect or verify the following categories of Personal Information from or about you in the following ways: 

• From applications, forms, communications and other interactions, including your name, address, e-mail address, telephone number, Social Security or other identification number, income, and source of funds. 

• From transactions made with or by Merrick Bank, information including your VISA® and MasterCard® transactions, loan performance and funds transfers.

• From entities outside of the Merrick Bank corporate family ("nonaffiliated third parties"), information including your creditworthiness/credit history and identity. These nonaffiliated third parties include consumer/credit-reporting agencies, verification services, entities that provide us with mailing lists, and publicly available reference sources.

• From your visits to our Web site, information including certain technical information about your computer and operating systems. Our Web site practices, including the use of "cookies," are described further on our Web site. A cookie is a file that identifies a computer as a unique user. Cookies may be used to facilitate your use of our Web site, to maintain site security and to improve our Web site. Most browsers are initially set up to accept cookies. You may be able to reset your browser to refuse all cookies or to indicate when a cookie is being sent. If cookies are disabled, however, our Web site (and other Web sites) may be harder to use. A cookie cannot read data stored on the hard drive of a computer. 

How do we use Personal Information?

We use Personal Information to operate our business in a prudent and efficient manner. This may include, depending on the nature of your relationship with us, using it to evaluate financial needs; offer products and services (such as our insurance offerings); process and service transactions; respond to inquiries and requests; fulfill our obligations to you; verify income, asset and obligation information; resolve disputes; prevent fraud; and perform risk control. Additionally, we may use your Personal Information to verify your identity, including, where applicable, verification in accordance with the USA PATRIOT Act.

Where permitted and appropriate, we may also use your Personal Information for Merrick Bank's marketing and product research and/or development purposes. Additionally, we use your Personal Information to comply with legal requirements, and in accordance with applicable laws, rules and regulations.

What Personal Information We Disclose and to Whom?

We may disclose all of the Personal Information (described above) that we collect about current and former customers as described in the following section to the following: 

• Affiliates (i.e., companies related to us by common control or ownership) of Merrick Bank Corporation and its parent, CardWorks, L.P.; and 

• Nonaffiliated third parties (i.e., third parties that are not members of our corporate family) such as financial service providers (i.e., VISA USA, Inc., MasterCard International, Incorporated, other banks and financial institutions, and insurance companies) and non-financial companies (i.e., retailers, direct marketers, marketing partners, and others). 

What Personal Information do we share internally among Merrick Bank companies and why do we share it?

In connection with the uses described above, we may, depending on the nature of your relationship with us, transfer some or all of your Personal Information to and among Merrick Bank's "affiliates" (i.e., companies related to us by common control or ownership such as CardWorks Servicing, LLC and CardWorks, Inc.).

Merrick Bank affiliates provide a number of crucial services to Merrick Bank in connection with the servicing and maintenance of our customers' accounts. Merrick Bank may share your Personal Information with affiliated third parties solely so that such affiliates can provide those services. Our affiliates are required to make contractual commitments to us to maintain the confidentiality of our customers' Personal Information. 

We are permitted under law to share Personal Information relating to our experiences or transactions with you or your account (such as your account balance and your payment history with us) with our affiliates. We also may share additional information about your account (such as information we receive from you in applications and information from credit reporting agencies) with our affiliates. You may direct us not to disclose to our affiliates information that does not relate solely to our or our affiliates' experiences or transactions with you (and your co-account holder or authorized user) or your account by completing the online Opt Out Form.  Please note that we are unable to process requests without an account number.

What Personal Information do we share externally with nonaffiliated third parties and why do we share it? 

Merrick Bank does not rent or sell Personal Information. In connection with the uses described above (for example, processing your application with us), we may, depending on the nature of your relationship with us, transfer some or all of your Personal Information to nonaffiliated third parties. These nonaffiliated third parties may be financial service providers (such as VISA USA, Inc., MasterCard International, Incorporated, other banks and financial institutions, and insurance companies), non-financial companies (such as government entities in response to subpoenas, consumer reporting agencies or technology companies) or others (such as professional services organizations or other service providers). 

To the extent the law permits, Merrick Bank may also disclose certain Personal Information to companies that perform marketing services on our behalf or to other financial institutions with which we have joint marketing agreements. This Personal Information includes: 

• Information we receive from you, including information you provide on applications or other forms, such as your name, address, social security number, assets and income; and

• Information about your transactions with our affiliates, others, or us such as your account balance, payment history, parties to transactions and credit card usage. 

Among other things, these nonaffiliated third parties (a) help us carry out and finalize transactions; (b) mail account statements and other information for us; (c) help us verify information, including identity; (d) provide us with consulting, accounting, legal and other services; (e) help us develop, operate and maintain our services and systems; and (f) where permitted and appropriate, perform marketing services for us or participate in joint marketing with us. These nonaffiliated third parties are required to protect the confidentiality and security of your Personal Information and to use it only in accordance with our instructions for the lawful purposes agreed. 

We may also transfer Personal Information (a) to government agencies, and regulatory and law enforcement authorities as necessary or required; (b) as part of the sale, merger or other disposition of a Merrick Bank business; (c) to other nonaffiliated third parties as requested by you or your authorized representative; and/or (d) as otherwise permitted or required by law, rule and/or regulation. 

How do we protect the confidentiality and security of Personal Information? 

• People. We educate our employees to treat Personal Information with care, and work to limit access to this information to individuals who need it for the purposes stated in this Pledge.

• Policies and procedures. We maintain and monitor our physical, electronic and procedural safeguards to comply with applicable regulations, updating them as needed so that we may protect Personal Information.

• Security. We take technical and organizational security measures, that are generally accepted in the industry as reasonable standards, to keep Personal Information confidential and secure against unauthorized or unlawful processing, and to prevent loss, destruction or damage.

• Children's Online Information Privacy. Merrick Bank typically provides consumer services to adults only and does not intend to collect or knowingly collect any information from or about children. It is possible that a child may impersonate an adult and attempt to apply for a Merrick Bank issued credit card or may apply for a consumer loan or other product. In so doing, they may provide their name, address, phone number, fax number, email address and other identifying information. When such information is received and Merrick Bank is aware that the individual providing the information is a child, the information is used only to reject the child's application. Such information is never shared with third parties. Merrick Bank cannot always determine if a visitor to its Web site or the sender of an email is a child.

• "Cookies." Our Web site makes use of a standard feature of browser software called a "cookie" to assign each visitor a unique, random number. Merrick Bank uses cookies that last only through a single session when visiting our Web site. However, to access the secured portions of the Web site, such as the Cardholder Center, you must allow cookies to be set. Again, a cookie cannot read data stored on the hard drive of a computer.

• Links to other sites. Web site contains links to other sites whose information practices may be different than ours. You should consult the other sites' privacy notices as Merrick Bank has no control over information that is submitted to, or collected by, these third parties and how that information is used. Please note that as you leave the Merrick Bank Web site, Merrick Bank does not transfer any information to these other sites. 

How can you verify that your Personal Information is accurate?

We endeavor to (a) keep Personal Information only for so long as is necessary for business purposes or to meet legal and regulatory requirements; and (b) keep our records of your Personal Information current and complete.

If you become aware of any discrepancies in your Personal Information, please notify us and we will make the necessary corrections. 

What if you have questions regarding this Pledge or our privacy practices?

Merrick Bank is responsible for ensuring that your questions are handled in accordance with this Pledge and applicable laws, rules and regulations. We will ensure that your legal rights have been protected and respected, and will address your concerns in a fair and timely manner. 

If you have any questions regarding this Pledge of our privacy-related practices, please contact us by e-mail at 

or you can write to us at: Merrick Bank, Attn: Privacy Officer, P.O. Box 5000, Draper, UT 84020-5000. You may also call the Customer Service number at (800) 253-2322.

For information on Merrick Bank, please visit our Web site at [www.merrickbank.com](http://www.merrickbank.com/). 

Special Notice for Vermont Residents

The information sharing practices described above are in accordance with Federal law. Vermont law places additional limits on sharing information about Vermont residents so long as they remain residents of Vermont. In accordance with Vermont law, Merrick Bank will not share information we collect about Vermont residents to companies outside of Merrick Bank except: 

• As permitted by law;

• To companies that perform marketing or other services on our behalf;

• Name, contact and transaction and experience information (such as your account balance and payment history) to other financial institutions with which we have joint marketing agreements;

• With the authorization or consent of the Vermont resident. 

Merrick Bank also will not share non-transactional information about Vermont residents received from others within the Merrick Bank family of companies except with the authorization or consent of the Vermont resident. 

Special Notice for California Residents

We only disclose your Personal Information with our affiliates and non-affiliated third parties in a manner that is permitted under the California Financial Information Privacy Act (CFIPA) and federal law. In general, CFIPA requires us (1) to provide you with notice and the right to tell us not to disclose your Personal Information before we disclose such information to our affiliates or other financial institutions with which we have joint marketing agreements, and (2) to seek your express consent before we disclose your Personal Information to non-affiliated third parties for marketing purposes. This means that unless we provide you with notice and the opportunity to tell us not to share your Personal Information, or seek your express consent to do so, we will not share your Personal Information with other financial service providers and non-financial parties except for the purpose of fulfilling your request for credit, as you may otherwise direct us to do so, or as otherwise permitted under CFIPA and federal law. You will receive a separate notice of your rights under the CFIPA. 

Thanks for Choosing Merrick Bank

Thank you for choosing Merrick Bank to provide you with the products and services you have selected. We appreciate your business and are committed to providing you confidential service. 

VISA is a registered trademark of VISA USA, Inc.  
MasterCard is a registered trademark of MasterCard International, Incorporated
